Joachim Tan

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

SUMMARY

I am currently a **Penultimate Computer** Science Major at the University Of Exeter. My interests are in **Full Stack Development** and Quantitative Trading.

I have always been interested in the inner workings of websites and applications. I wrote my first few programs in **Python** guided by a book that my parents had bought. The time spent working on them brought me much joy.

I had my first formal coding class when I enrolled in Singapore Polytechnic. I had so much fun doing school projects that I took on my own side projects, making telegram bots and coding a system in C++ that would record my online shop sales. The experience made me fall in love with the process of building products that improve our lives.

During my National Service, I continued pursuing my interest by taking online courses on SEO, Django, Figma & React. These skills helped me build my own website and host my expense tracker telegram bot using Heroku.

CONTACT



Hello@JoachimStanislaus.com



oachimStanislaus.com



oachimStanislaus



oachimStanislaus



RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst

SG Enable

May 2022 - Present

- Tools: Python, Openpyxl, Pandas, PyQt5.
- Lead & Developed software to generate graphs and automate data collection & data sorting. Reduced time taken to analyze data by 50%.
- Manipulating Data to gain further insights, predict trends & sudden spikes in assistance requests to better prepare infrastructure to meet sudden demand.

Instructor

Little Coder

Jan 2022 - Present

- Languages: Python, Java, Lua, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS
- Software: Scratch, Visual Studio
- Teach and conduct coding, STEM and technology related classes and programs.

Engineering Intern

Royal Dutch Shell

Mar 2019 - Aug 2019

- Communicated with the Reliability Department stakeholders on their needs.
- Proposed and developed a solution using VBA that reduced time taken to analyze data by 50%.

EDUCATION

Bsc Computer Science

University Of Exeter

2022-2024

- Entry Into 2nd Year.
- Founding Team of the UK Singapore STEM Society (Officer Head)

Diploma in Computer Engineering

Singapore Polytechnic

2017-2020

- Vice Captain & Treasurer of the Waterpolo Team

PROJECTS

Climate Hack Hackathon 2022

Team Leader, Technical Lead

SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, C++, Java, VBA, Lua, React.js

Tools: Figma, DJango, Git, Bulma, Bootstrap, Bulma